Peter Heffernan

Results oriented multi-disciplined Human Resources Director with a proven record of accomplishment across all phases of the Human Resources function. Extensive experience leading and building out HR teams while conducting many of the activities myself when necessary in start-up organizations that were scaling.

Bedford, MA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Peter-Heffernan/294c4ece4f7fe591

WORK EXPERIENCE

HR Manager

Russian School of Mathematics - Newton, MA - 2013 to 2014

Responsibilities

Focused on sourcing and hiring primarily Java Engineers & Math Teachers in Mass. and California.

- Created the sourcing program to develop pipelines of talent using a variety of sourcing tools
- Developed and implemented a College Campus Recruiting and an Employee Referral program

Accomplishments

Sourced & directly hired 2 senior level Java Engineers and 15 Math Teachers without agency fees

Senior Consultant Recruiter (Consulting role)

Boston Children's Hospital - Boston, MA - January 2013 to March 2013

I focused on talent acquisition for hard to fill technical positions in IT and Clinical Operations. I hired 1 Interactive Designer, 2 Java Engineers, 1 Technical Project Manager, (was open for 6 months) 2 SR. Net Engineer roles in Cardiology, 1 Medical Technology Research position (was open for 14 months) and one Medical Coordinator role.

Director Human Resources

VISIBLE TECHNOLOGIES - Burlington, MA - 2010 to 2012

Visible is a leader in Social Media monitoring, analytics, and service for enterprises globally. Seattle based Visible purchased Cymfony (Burlington MA).

Director Human Resources (Company relocating to Bellevue WA)

Responsible for managing and coordinating all day-to-day HR activities and programs for this VC backed expansion stage company. Report to the CEO. Provide Compensation, Benefits, Organizational Development and Recruiting to C level management team with groups in Boston, Seattle and London.

- Led the integration efforts combining Cymfony and Visible Benefits Programs, developing and rolled out new benefit programs. Streamlined benefit processed saving \$100,000.
- Rolled out Corporate Values and weekly VP communications forum.
- Established market based compensation and benefits programs
- Drove all recruiting efforts for the company including senior hires such as a CTO, VP of Sales, Client Services Director, Product Marketing Head, Director of Cloud Computing & IT operations. Zero agencies recruiting costs incurred.
- Implemented company-wide programs Skills Safari (Training & development); eKale job evaluation (Compensation Program); Culpepper surveys (benchmarking); 360 performance reviews

Senior Corporate Recruiter

THE MATHWORKS - Natick, MA - 2008 to 2009

· Responsible for sourcing and hiring for the Professional Recruiting Group.

- Sourced and hired 12 key employees for Business Applications and Marketing Groups.
- Championed and implemented recruiting events for Java Developers in the local Java community.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Business Studies in Human Resources

Dublin City University - Dublin

SKILLS

extensive experience in Talent Acquisition, Talent Management, Social Media Recruiting, Compensation and Benefits at a Senior Management level in both global and start-up companies

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/in/peterheffernan